naturallivingideas.com 2019-12-26

# Privacy Policy

This privacy policy sets out how NaturalLivingIdeas.com (“Website”) uses and protects any information that you provide when you use this website.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting it. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you what personally identifiable information we may collect and how it may be used.

### What Information We Collect & How We Use It

**Information You Voluntarily Submit**

In some cases we may collect information such as your name, email address and any other requested details when you voluntarily fill out a form to provide these details. For example, if you subscribe to our email newsletter or fill out a contact form. If you subscribe to our email newsletter, we will store your email address in our email auto-responder account (Aweber) and may periodically email you with our email newsletter. You can unsubscribe from this at any time by clicking an unsubscribe link found at the bottom of any of our emails. 

**Information We Automatically Collect**

We automatically collect some non-personally identifiable information when you browse the website – such as the device you are using, browser and operating system. This is so we can serve the correct website layout to suit your requirements, including image sizes and ad sizes. 

We also collect IP address, the referring source (how you arrived at the website), pages you browse while on the website and how long you navigate the website, and in some cases we track external clicks to other websites. 

### Cookies 

We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by the Website. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website. 

The Website uses cookies to deliver a more personalized experience while browsing the Website. For example, to suggest more relevant content or advertising. 

You can disable the use of cookies in your internet browser. You can also remove previously set cookies from within your browser. Some website services may become unavailable when cookies are disables. 

### How Your Information May Be Used

  * To serve the correct website layout to your specific device or browser. 
  * To send you email newsletters or Push Notifications when you specifically opt-in to these services.
  * To respond to your comments or enquiries.
  * To provide you with user support.
  * To track and measure website performance and functionality. 
  * To track and measure marketing and advertising performance.
  * To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity. 

### Third Party Use Of Personal Information

We may share your information with third parties when you explicitly authorize us to share your information.

Additionally, the Website may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the Website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policies.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

**Google Analytics:** This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics. 

**Aweber:** This service is used to deliver our email newsletter. We store only your email address and you can unsubscribe at any time by clicking an unsubscribe link in any of our email communications. Please refer to [Aweber’s Privacy Policy](https://www.aweber.com/privacy.htm) here. 

Except when required by law, we will not sell, distribute, or reveal your email addresses or other personal information without your consent; however, we may disclose or transfer personal information collected through the Website to third parties who acquire all or a portion of our business, which may be the result of a merger, consolidation, or purchase of all or a portion of our assets, or in connection with any bankruptcy or reorganization proceeding brought by or against us. 

### Advertising

**Display Ads**

The Website uses Mediavine to manage all third-party advertising on the Website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the Website, which may use cookies. Mediavine may collect IP addresses and location to serve personalized ads.  If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. 

**Affiliate Program Participation**

The Website may engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding tracking links into the Website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

**Amazon Affiliate Disclosure**

NaturalLivingIdeas.com is a participant in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for sites to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com or endless.com, MYHABIT.com, SmallParts.com, or AmazonWireless.com. Pages on this site may include affiliate links to Amazon and its affiliate sites on which the owner of this website will make a referral commission. 

### Rights Related To Your Personal Information

Access: You may access the personal information we hold about you by email info@naturallivingideas.com

Remove: If you’d like to remove any personal information we hold about you, you can do so by emailing info@naturallivingideas.com 

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law. 

### Contact Us

Please contact info@naturallivingideas.com with any questions related to this Privacy Policy. 

**Last Updated June 10th, 2019**
